It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Came from a place far away, Musashi and Senhime's group has fought against Hanzō with all their force.
멀리서 와서 홋카이도를 무대로 총력을 다해 싸운 한조와 무사시, 센히메 일행.
After a long fight, Onihime died, and Jiraiyan has moved by Musashi's teamwork.
기나긴 싸움 끝에 오니히메는 죽고, 지라이얀도 무사시의 팀워크에 넘어갔다.
And Hanzō has gone with Karakuri Stronghold.
그리고 한조는 카라쿠리 요새와 함께.
The Most Evil!
악이라면 제일!
Hanzō Revives
한조의 부활이오
This feels good!
기분 좋다!
In Edo Castle, a celebrating party was going on, for Senhime, who was called back by Ieyasu.
에도 성에서는 이에야스의 귀국 명령으로 돌아온 센히메를 위해 경사 잔치가 펼쳐지고 있었다.
Senhime, please be prepared soon. Lord Ieyasu is waiting very much.
센히메 님, 슬슬 준비해 주세요. 이에야스 님이 몹시 기다리고 계십니다.
Got it! I'll be there soon!
네! 지금 나갑니다!
We've waited for you-dasu!
기다렸소!
You sure did.
기다렸지.
Musashi, your mouth.
무사시, 침 삼켜라.
You look quite different, Senhime!
몰라보겠구나, 센히메!
Of course.
당연.
Oh, Mr. Ayamaro!
아, 아야마로 님.
Mr. Ieyasu, please introduce her to me.
이에야스 님, 소개해 주시지요.
Oh, Hime, you should greet Mr. Aburakoji!
아, 이 기회에, 히메, 아부라코지 님에게 인사를!
Senhime, nice to meet you!
센히메 님, 처음 뵙겠소!
As all of you are here, what a joyous day!
자, 일동 모였으니 오늘은 경사롭다, 경사로워!
Jūbee, you can eat now!
자, 주베, 먹어라!
Yessir. Then I'll start with boiled fish.
예. 그럼 먼저 조림부터.
Hime, as you wanted, I've had them prepare all the foods you like!
자, 자, 히메, 네가 좋아하는 것만 모아 두었으니 잘 먹어라!
Mr. Aburakoji, east as much as you want!
아부라코지 님도 사양말고!
Then putting aside ranks!
그럼 마음놓고 먹겠소!
Who is that ugly man-dasu?
저 못생긴 남자는 누구이오?
Huh?
어?
Aburakoji Ayamaro is the 13th boy of the historic imperial court of Miyako Palace.
미야코 팰리스의 유서 깊은 조정의 13번째 남아, 아부라코지 아야마로 님.
It seems that the feudal lord has invited him for the sightseeing of Edotopia.
이번엔 성주님이 에도토피아 구경을 위해 초대하신 듯 합니다.
By thew way, he somehow looks like he's without any grace...
그러고 보니 어쩐지 기품이 있는지 없는지...
He is just like you, if you move around eyes and a nose.
눈코 위치만 바뀌면 너하고 딱 똑같네, 무사시.
(Specialty of Hokkaido)
(홋카이도 특산품)
These are hairy crabs, from the present of the princess!
공주님께서의 선물, 진미 털게입니다.
-What an excellent product! -Isn't that right?!
-오, 훌륭하구나! -그렇지?!
Crabs are my favorite food, too!
게는 저도 크게 좋아하오!
Oh, good for you! Well, eat as much as you want!
아, 그, 그건 잘 됐소! 많이 먹으시오.
Hey, my crab!
아, 내 게!
Isn't it great, Hime? Mr. Ayamaro is happy about this, too!
괜찮지 않나, 히메. 아야마로 님도 기뻐하고 있잖니.
Look, it's potherb roll that you like, Hime!
봐봐, 히메가 좋아하는 나물 단고야!
Here, here!
자, 자!
It truly is a delicacy!
진미이오!
Lord Ieyasu has called us back urgently. Could this be a marriage interview?
이에야스 님의 급한 귀국 명령. 이건 혹시 맞선 상대?
Marriage interview?!
맞선?!
Shh!
쉬잇!
It's over, it's over, and the meal was great! Now I'm free-dasu!
끝이오, 끝났소, 먹었소, 잘 먹었소! 이걸로 난 자유이오!
That's truly much appreciated.
그건, 그건 수고했습니다.
I am the one who've gone through a deep inner struggle. Musashi was torturing my heart.
마음고생한 건 나다. 무사시가 날 귀찮게 해서 배가 아팠구만.
You are doing that because you couldn't eat crabs. How sickening-dasu.
게 못 먹은 거 주제에 아니꼬운 놈이오.
What?!
뭐야?!
Well, that's enough! You two should get a rest.
이제 됐다. 둘 다 푹 쉬어라.
I'm entrusting them to you, Mr. Zenigatan.
잘 부탁합니다, 제니가탄 님.
Alright! Understood.
예, 알겠습니다!
Now, follow me, you two! It's not a clean place, but still you can take a good rest there.
자자, 오세요, 둘 다! 더러운 곳이지만 제 집에서 일단 쉬시라.
That's right-dasu! We'll take a rest-dasu!
그렇소! 푹 쉬오!
Mr. Zenigatan, I will leave here.
제니가탄 님. 저는 여기서.
Huh? Aren't you coming to my home? There's no need to decline.
어라? 제 집에 안 오쇼? 사양할 필요 없습니다만.
I appreciate your suggestion, but I would like to think again about what I have learned during the trip alone in silence.
제안은 기쁘지만 여행에서 여럿 배운 것을 혼자 조용히 다시 생각해 보고 싶습니다.
I see. You really are different!
그렇구려. 역시 말하는 게 다르군!
Then, excuse me.
그럼 실례하겠습니다.
See ya, Kojirō-!
그럼, 코지로!
What?! Me?!
어?! 내가?!
Right. Guide him Edo Castle.
그래, 에도 성을 안내해 줘라.
No way! Why do I have to please that Mr. Aburakoji, grandpa?!
무슨! 왜 내가 저 아부라코지 씨 비위를 맞추어야 하는 거야, 할아버지?!
T- that person is important to you, too. Please do that, will you?
저, 저 분은 네게도 중요한 분. 싫어하지 말고 수고해라, 어?
Oh, Ms. Senhime, you were here!
아, 센히메 씨, 여기에 오셨습니까!
Then please guide me!
그럼 안내해 주시지요!
M- Ms. Senhime, wait for me! Please walk slower!
세, 센히메 씨! 기다려 주시오, 조금만 더 느리게!
Wait-
기다리-
W- why?!
어, 어째서!
Tag game is over!
술래잡기는 끝이오!
Really!
진짜!
Mr. Aburakoji!
아부라코지 님!
I don't want to play with you!
너 따위하고 놀고 싶지 않아!
More...
더...
Hey, we're back!
어이, 지금 돌아왔다!
Welcome back, dear.
어서 와, 당신.
It's been a while, Mr. Musashi!
오랜만이네, 무사시 씨.
Huh? You must be...
어라? 당신은...
Are you Ms. Akane? W- why are you here-dasu?
설마 아카네 씨? 왜 여기에 있소?
Why, eh? She's my wife!
음, 왜냐니. 내 마누라다.
Wife?!
마누라?!
So, are you the boss' wife, Ms. Akane?!
이? 아카네 씨가 두목 마누라?!
Thanks to what you did back then. I still appreciate what you did.
그 때 덕분이야. 정말 무사시 씨에게 감사하고 있어.
That's what happened, you know.
그러니까, 그런 거야.
(in a Kabuki show, one would shout name when one's favorite actor shows up - 掛け声, kakegoe)
-요! 일본 제일! 카라쿠리야! -(나왔다!)
Beautiful.
아름답군.
Excellent.
훌륭해.
(決まった, kimatta is an usual reaction to a peak acting in a Kabuki play, but not his physical action)
이거야!
You idiot! You're blocking my sight!
무식한 놈아! 안 보인다!
Sit down, you dimwit!
물러나라, 바보 자식아!
What is this upward ponytail?!
뭐야, 이 머리꼭지는?
It must be a martial swallow!
제비가 무예하네!
Something smells tasty-dasu.
맛있는 냄새이오.
Oh, I'm sorry. Were you that hungry?
어라, 미안해. 그렇게나 배고팠어?
Uh, no, not really...
아, 아니, 그런 건...
Huh?
어라?
It's almost done, so keep calm and wait like a good kid.
이제 곧이니까 착한 아이처럼 기다려.
Good kid... is it-dasu?
착한 아이... 이오...
Behave! I have to put my mouth on that later!
적당히 좀 해라. 나중에 나도 입 대는 거야.
It was a perfect tea.
훌륭한 차였소이다.
Ugh, that's filthy!
아, 더러워.
What should I do?
이걸 어쩐담...
This leaves me no choice.
이렇게 된 바...
A cockroach!
아! 바퀴벌레!
Where, where?! I despise cockroaches!
어디, 어디에! 난 바퀴벌레가 정말 싫소이다!
Hot, hot!
뜨거, 뜨거!
Don't hold back and eat as much as you want, Mr. Musashi!
자, 사양말고 잔뜩 먹으쇼, 무사시 씨.
Yeah. Try this too! It's good.
그래. 아, 이것도 맛있어.
Oh, is that so-dasu...
어, 그렇소...
Since you're young, you gotta eat well!
젊으니까 팍팍 먹어야지!
Here! Eat some of these too!
여기! 이것도 먹어라!
Thank you-dasu!
고맙소!
(天神, tenjin: the sky deity in Japanese folk religion Shinto, considered the same with the thunder god)
(천신: 일본 민간신앙 신토 신, 뇌신하고 동일하게 취급)
Dear, let's go for the memorial ceremony for the sky deity!
저기, 여보. 밥 다 먹으면 셋이서 천신 제사제에 가자.
Hey, that's a good idea!
오, 그거 좋네!
T- the memorial ceremony?
제, 제사제이오?
Right. We must pray so that Musashi will become a splendid martial artist!
그래, 무사시 씨가 훌륭한 무예가가 될 수 있도록 기도해야지.
Yeah, that's right! You sure know what to do, Akane!
응, 그렇지! 좋은 생각이네, 아카네!
Mr. Musashi, do you like ceremonies?
무사시 씨, 제사제 좋아?
I love them-dasu!
정말 좋소!
If you say so, I gotta finish this up as soon as possible!
그래! 그렇다면 빨리 먹어버려야지.
It's not good for your body if you hurry like that.
그렇게 허둥대면 몸에 안 좋아, 여보.
It's not good-dasu!
안 좋소!
Yes. It's beautiful. Too beautiful that it scares me.
음, 아름다워. 내가 봐도 무서울 정도다.
You must not let your guards down.
방심하면 안 된다.
Dontaku
돈타쿠
Understood.
알겠다.
What?! Hanzō was alive!
무슨! 한조는 살아 있었다!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
What do you think about this, miss? Fried dangos are good, too!
아가씨, 어때? 구운 단고도 맛있어!
All the people around here likes events and ceremonies. By the way, do you want to eat some dangos?
이 주변 사람들은 다들 행사를 좋아하니까. 어떠냐, 단고라도 먹을텨?
Hey, sweet red bean soup is better!
어라, 단팥죽 쪽이 더 좋아.
I'm already full now-dasu!
나, 이제 배부르오!
No way! Don't want want 2 or 3 lines of dangos in your mouth?
뭔 소리냐! 단고 2줄이나 3줄 입에 안 넣으려?
Yeah, it's you, Mr. Musashi! That sweet red bean soup tastes good!
그래, 무사시 씨잖아. 저 가게 단팥죽 맛있어.
I want to try both-dasu!
둘 다 먹어보고 싶소.
Well, yeah, then! Let's begin with dangos! Follow me!
자, 그래, 그래! 일단 단고다! 따라와!
Hey, isn't it you who want that?
저런, 당신이 먹고 싶은 거 아냐?
H- hey! That's same for you!
무, 무슨! 그건 마찬가지잖아?
You knew it!
들켰나.
No, I'd like that more!
아니, 저걸로!
Huh? Hey, what's wrong?
어? 어이, 왜 그러냐?
Does your stomach hurt?
어디 배라도 아프니?
You sure about that? Aren't you sick?
정말이냐? 속이라도 안 좋거나 한 거 아냐?
Mr. Musashi, you don't have to overdo it. If you do feel sick, then tell us.
무사시 씨, 무리 안 해도 좋아. 속이 안 좋으면 말해.
Boss, Ms. Akana, thank you-dasu!
두목, 아카네 씨, 고맙소.
That was so sudden, Mr. Musashi!
갑자기 왜 그러냐, 무사시 씨!
I do not know how does my mother look ever since I was born-dasu.
나, 태어났을 때부터 엄마 얼굴은 모르오.
I was alone all the time, and only Otsuru became a friend with me-dasu.
쭉 혼자로 사이좋게 같이 있어 준 건 오츠루밖에 없었소.
I am so grateful for doing all this to me!
이렇게까지 받아서, 나...
What is this guy doing in the middle of street?
뭐야, 얘, 길 한복판에서?
Huh? Are you crying, bro?
어라? 울고 있어, 형?
Isn't this guy just a bumpkin who got lost?
길이라도 잃어버린 촌놈 아니야?
Like, weh, where am I?
우엥, 여긴 어디야, 하고 말야.
No doubt about it!
틀림없어!
What was that for?!
뭔 짓이야!
Was it that weird, huh?
그렇게 이상하냐, 엉?
Is someone crying that strange? You sure have a big mouth, you know.
사람이 울고 있는 게 그렇게 이상하냐? 멍청하게 입만 살아가지곤.
Your erected uvula is giving trouble to people!
니놈 목젖이 발기해서 피해를 주고 있잖냐!
If you can't handle your big mouth, should I fasten your lips?
그거 못 숙이겠으면 내가 그 입을 꼬매 줄까?
Zenigatan sir! I didn't recognize you...
제니가탄 나리! 잘 못 알아봐서...
I won't forgive you again if you ever say something like that again, you bastard!
쓸데없는 소리 더 하면 용서 안 한다, 이 자식아!
I apologize! Sorry!
죄송합니다! 미안해요!
Wait for me!
같이 가!
I'm sorry for that.
미안허이. 부끄러운 모습 보여서.
Mr. Musashi, if you could, you can stay in our home as long as you want. Right, dear?
무사시 씨, 괜찮으면 언제까지나 우리 집에 있어도 돼. 그렇지, 여보?
Of course, why not? If you'd like, you can call me dad, you know!
물론, 그렇고말고! 내가 괜찮으면, 아빠라고 불러주던가 하고!
I'm mom, then.
나는 엄마.
Boss...
두목...
I'm happy-dasu!
기쁘오!
This will do. Forgive me, grandpa!
이걸로 OK. 할아버지, 용서해.
Bye-bye!
바이바이!
Finally we got rid of Senhime!
드디어 센히메를 죽였군!
Senhime!
센히메 님!
Who's there?!
뭔 일이냐!
Invaders! Everyone gather!
수상한 놈이다! 모두 나와라!
Hanzō! Were you alive?!
한조! 살아 있었냐!
I told you I am invincible.
나는 불사신이라 말했을 터.
Do not let him leave the castle! Get him!
성에서 나가게 두지 마라! 꼭 잡아라!
Musashi! Musashi!
무사시! 무사시!
Who's there, in this deep night?
누구여, 이 밤중에?
Y- you escaped from the castle?!
서, 성에서 도망쳐 나왔다고?!
That's a mess-dasu!
너무 무턱댔소.
Whatever! It's too late now! Let's go on a trip again together!
틀렸어. 이미 늦었어. 같이 또 여행가자!
-Uh, you know, Hime... -I've made a decision. Castle life is boring and stifling!
-아, 아니, 그게, 히메... -나, 결정했어. 성 생활 따위 지루하고 답답해!
And marriage with that guy?!
게다가 그 인간하고 맞선?!
Even thinking about him is gross.
생각하는 것만으로 기분 나빠.
He didn't look like a bad guy-dasu...
그렇게 나쁜 놈으로는 안 보였소...
Then you go marry him!
그럼 니가 같이 살아!
-Boss! This is bad! S- Senhime is... -not there!
-두목! 큰일입니다! 세, 센히메 님이... -없소!
You're here?
계셔?!
Hey, Kojirō!
아, 코지로다!
Oh, Senhime!
아, 센히메 님!
Hey, it's hard to walk here-dasu!
잠깐, 이건 걷기 힘드오.
I am more than enough for the guard of Senhime!
센히메 님 경호는 나 혼자서 충분하다!
Grandpa!
할아버지!
Oh, Hime!
오, 히메!
-It's good to know that you're safe! -I was worried about you since your coverlet was empty!
-무사해서 다행이야! -아, 너야말로 이불이 텅 비어 있어서 걱정했다!
I'm sorry, but you know...
미안해. 그래도 말야...
What a relief! I worried so much! Everyone, protect my princess properly!
정말 잘 되었소! 나도 걱정에 걱정을! 모두 내 공주를 똑바로 지키쇼!
Who's your princess?!
누가 니 공주야?!
That will nonetheless eventually happen.
어차피 그렇게 될 거잖소.
And you know that.
이미 알고 있는 주제에.
Feudal lord! Senhime is safe.
영주님! 센히메 님은 무사합니다!
Great. Did you find Hanzō yet?
그래! 한조는 찾았느냐?
Not yet, but I will find him no matter what.
그게 아직입니다. 그렇지만 반드시 찾아내겠습니다.
Really, trying to take over the country instead of me is unforgivable!
정말, 내 대신 천하를 쥐어잡겠다니, 단연코 용서할 수 없다!
Yessir! I, Jūbee, will protect your life risking my own body!
예! 영주님의 생명, 이 주베가 제 몸을 걸고 지켜 드리겠습니다.
It's surprising that Hanzō's still alive-dasu, but with this level of guard in place, he's really gonna be done for this time-dasu.
한조가 살아 있었다니 놀랐소이만, 이 엄한 경호 앞에선 이번에야말로 끝이오.
You must not look down of Hanzō.
그 한조라는 자, 얕보는 건 금물이다.
There's nobody here.
아무도 없소.
You bastard!
네이놈!
Grandpa!
할아버지!
I'm scared!
무섭소!
That's Jūbee I know.
역시 주베.
Hanzō!
한조!
Ieyasu, I will take your life!
이에야스! 그 목숨 가져가겠다!
Take one more!
한 채 더 가지!
Damn!
저런!
Hanzō! You aren't getting away-dasu!
한조! 못 달아나오!
Tch! That's all for today!
쳇! 오늘은 여기까지 하지!
Get him! He ran to outside!
잡아라! 놈은 바깥으로 달아났다!
You bastard! You aren't getting away!
이 놈! 못 도망간다!
Anyway, the one in Hanzō's breast width has a suspicious plan written on it.
결국 한조의 품에 있던 것. 수상한 계획임이 틀림없습니다.
(Saikai-do: lit. West Sea Circuit. These administrative districts were used before Muromachi Era. Shiranui: Atmospheric ghost light told in Kyūshū)
사이카이 왕국의 시라누이 일족이라?
Well then! Am I good to go, grandpa?
정해졌네! 괜찮지, 할아버지?
Uh, but... no matter what, Kyushu is far away.
에, 그렇지만... 뭐가 어떻든 규슈는 멀다.
If you say no, then I'll leave home!
안 된다고 하면 가출할 거야!
What?! Leave home?!
어? 가출?
That's bad...
곤란하네...
Feudal lord, Senhime has become familiar with long trips, and as long as Mr. Kojirō and Mr. Musashi as her guards...
영주님. 센히메 님도 여행에 익숙해졌기도 하고, 코지로 님과 무사시 님을 경호로 붙인다면.
Well, that's right. Senhime never listen to me no matter what I say.
어, 그렇구나. 아무리 말해도 안 듣는 센히메이니 어쩔 수 없나.
Yes!
좋아!
And that's how their journey full of incident has begun once again.
이렇게 다시 셋의 온갖 일 다 일어나는 모험이 시작되었다.
What kind of wonderful man would be in the kingdom of Saikai?
사이카이 왕국에는 어떤 근사한 사내가 있을까?
The hunter of love Senhime is growing restless in her trip to Kyushu.
규슈에 여행가는 사랑의 사냥꾼 센히메의 마음은 들뜬다.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
Just because I entered dango quick eating contest I fought with Kojirō,
단고 빨리 먹기 콩쿠르에 출전했다는 이유만으로 코지로하고 싸우고, 오센짱은 시라누이 일족에게 잡히고, 엉망진창!
At that moment, I met Mr. Saigo and Mr. Ryoma who I didn't see for a long time-dasu!
그 때, 사이고 씨하고 오랜만에 료마 씨하고 만났소!
Osenchan, wait for me! I'm going to rescue you-dasu!
오센짱, 기다리시오! 내가 구하러 가오!
Next story! Mr. Saigo is a Mysterious Person
다음 이야기! 사이고 씨는 수수께끼의 인물이오
(翔ぶが如く, Tobu ga Gotoku: lit. as if in flight. Historical fiction written by Shiba Ryōtaro, where one of main character is Saigō Takamori)
질풍노도의 "나는 듯이"이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Mr. Saigo is
사이고 씨는
a Mysterious Person
수수께끼의 인물
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!